SEONJIN NA

Phone: +1 404-259-3240 Email: sna42@gatech.edu

Github: https://github.com/seonjinna Website: https://seonjinna.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a postdoctoral researcher at Georgia Tech supervised by Prof. Hyesoon Kim. Before joining Georgia Tech, I received a Ph.D. in Computer Science from KAIST (2023) advised by Prof. Jaehyuk Huh. My research interests lie in GPU architecture, trusted computing, heterogeneous systems, distributed computing, and systems for machine learning. During my Ph.D. studies, I focused on developing a secure architecture designed to extend a trusted execution environment (TEE) on accelerators, including GPUs and NPUs, while maintaining minimal performance overhead. Currently, I am actively engaged in extending my research field to address various challenges in the multi-GPU system, systems for machine learning, and accelerating large language models.

EMPLOYMENT

Georgia Institute of Technology

June. 2023 - present

Postdoctoral Fellow, School of Computer Science

Supervisor: Hyesoon Kim

Microsoft Research Asia

Mar. 2019 - June. 2019

Visiting Fellow

Supervisors: Lintao Zhang & Yunxin Liu

EDUCATION

KAIST Mar. 2018 - Feb. 2023

Doctor of Philosophy, School of Computing

Advisor: Jaehyuk Huh

KAIST Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2018

Master of Science, School of Computing

Advisor: Jaehyuk Huh

Sogang University Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2016

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Summa Cum Laude

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Accelerating GPU Simulation for Machine Learing Workloads

April. 2024 - Present

- · Investigated the limitations of prior studies designed for GPU simulation acceleration.
- · Proposed a statistical-based sampling scheme to reduce GPU simulation time significantly.
- · Contributed as **second author** to discuss the main ideas and conduct experiments.
- · Under Review

Efficient Row-Hammer Mitigation

Sep. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the limitations of previous row-hammer mitigation mechanisms.
- · Proposed row-hammer mitigation with lower metadata overhead compared to previous works.

- · Contributed as **second author** to discuss the main ideas and conduct experiments.
- · Work-in-progress

SSD Aware GPU Thread Block Scheduling Mechanism

Sep. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the problem of previous GPU memory safety mechanisms.
- · Proposed power-side channel attack mitigation mechanisms for GPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** to discuss the main ideas, conduct experiments, and write papers.
- · Under Review

Efficient GPU Address Translation

Sep. 2023 - Present

- \cdot Proposed efficient address translation mechanism for the multi-GPU system.
- · Contributed as **second author** to discuss the main ideas and analyze experimental results.
- · Under Review

GPU Power Side-channel Attack Defense Mechanism

June. 2023 - Present

- \cdot Investigated the problem of previous GPU memory safety mechanisms.
- · Proposed power-side channel attack mitigation mechanisms for GPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** to discuss the main ideas and conduct experimental results.
- · Under Review

Efficient GPU Memory Safety Technique

June. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the problem of previous GPU memory safety mechanisms.
- · Proposed a practical GPU memory safety mechanism with low-performance overhead.
- · Contributed as **fourth author** to conduct experiments, and analyze result.
- · Under Review

Privacy-aware ML Program Cloning

June. 2023 - Present

- · Investigated the privacy-aware tracing mechanism to prevent DNN model extraction attacks.
- · Contributed as first author to conduct experiments, implement the main ideas, and lead the project.
- · Work-in-progress

NPU Side-channel Attack Protection

Jan. 2022 - Present

- · Investigated the side-channel attack-based vulnerability of execution on NPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** to conduct motivational experiments, discuss the main ideas, and help writing.
- · Work-in-progress

Dynamic Secure-granularity Management for Heterogeneous Systems Jan. 2022 - Present

- · Investigated the performance bottleneck of heterogeneous processors.
- · Contributed as **second author** by conducting motivational experiments, discussing the main ideas, and writing.
- · Under Review

Efficient On-chip Memory Management and Scheduling on NPUs Dec. 2021 - Jul. 2023

- · Analyzed the data dependency of tensor computations in DNN training.
- · Proposed an efficient on-chip memory management and scheduling policy to improve DNN training performance on NPUs.
- · Contributed as **second author** by discussing the main ideas, conducting motivational experiments, and writing.
- · Published in MICRO 2023

Trusted Multi-GPU Architecture

Sep. 2021 - Present

- · Investigated the performance overhead of prior secure communication techniques on a multi-GPU system.
- · Analyzed the communication patterns of GPU workloads and performance degradation of secure communication.
- · Proposed an efficient data protection technique to minimize the secure communication overhead.
- · Contributed as **first author** to implement the simulator, conduct experiments, and lead the project.
- · Published in HPCA 2024

Efficient Memory Protection Mechanism for Secure NPU

Sep. 2020 -March. 2021

- · Investigated a significant performance degradation of CPU memory protection schemes on NPUs.
- · Proposed selective memory protection and multi-granular counter mode encryption techniques.
- · Contributed as **second author** to implement simulator, discuss the main ideas, and conduct motivational experiments.
- · Published in ICCD 2022

Trusted NPU Architecture

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021

- · Extended the existing CPU TEE design to isolate the NPU execution context from OS.
- · Proposed a tree-less integrity protection by exploiting a tensor-based NPU execution model.
- · Contributed as **third author** to implement the simulator, discuss the main ideas, and conduct motivational experiments.
- · Published in HPCA 2022

Efficient Memory Protection Mechanism for Secure GPU Memory Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

- · Analyzed memory update behaviors of GPU benchmarks and real-world applications using the NVbit.
- · Proposed an efficient GPU memory protection technique leveraging the uniform memory update behavior of GPU workloads.
- · Contributed as first author to implement and evaluate the main ideas and lead the project.
- · Published in **HPCA 2021**

Machine Learning Inference on Mobiles

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

- · Analyzed the performance characterization of mobile ML inferences using the TensorFlow Lite framework.
- · This project was done during the Microsoft Research Asia internship.

Hardware Prefetching

Mar. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Investigated and analyzed the performance of HW-based prefetching techniques on the CPU system.
- · Implemented HW-based prefetching techniques on Gem5 simulator.

PUBLICATIONS

- Seonjin Na, Jungwo Kim, Sunho Lee, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Supporting Secure Multi-GPU Computing with Dynamic and Batched Metadata Management", the 30th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA), March 2024.
- · Jungwoo Kim, <u>Seonjin Na</u>, Sanghyeon Lee, Sunho Lee, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Improving Data Reuse in NPU On-chip Memory with Interleaved Gradient Order for DNN Training", the 56th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture (MICRO), October 2023.
- · Sunho Lee, **Seonjin Na**, Jungwoo Kim, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Tunable Memory Protection for Secure Neural Processing Units", the 40th IEEE International Conference on Computer Design (ICCD), October 2022.

- · Sunho Lee, Jungwoo Kim, **Seonjin Na**, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "TNPU: Supporting Trusted Execution with Tree-less Integrity Protection for Neural Processing Unit", the 28th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (**HPCA**), February 2022.
- · <u>Seonjin Na</u>, Sunho Lee, Yeonjae Kim, Jongse Park, and Jaehyuk Huh, "Common Counters: Compressed Encryption Counters for Secure GPU Memory", the 27th IEEE International Symposium on High-Performance Computer Architecture (HPCA), February 2021.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Georgia Institute of Technology

June. 2023 - Present

· Postdoctoral Researcher, Advisor: Hyesoon Kim

Microsoft Research Asia

Mar. 2019 - Jun. 2019

· Research Intern, Advisor: Lintao Zhang, Yunxin Liu

KAIST

Mar. 2016 - Present

· Graduate Research Assistant & Teaching Assistant

PATENTS

Dynamic One-time Pad Table Management for Secure Multi-GPU Communication

- · Jaehyuk Huh, **Seonjin Na**, Jungwoo Kim, Sunho Lee
- · Korea Patent; Pending

Improving the Utilization of NPU On-chip Memory with Computation Rearrangement for DNN Training

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Jungwoo Kim, Seonjin Na, Sanghyeon Lee, Sunho Lee
- · Korea Patent; Pending

Apparatus and Method for Providing Secure Execution Environment for NPU

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Sunho Lee, **Seonjin Na**
- · US Patent (With Samsung Electronics); Pending

Hardware-based Security Architecture for Trusted Neural Processing Unit

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Sunho Lee, Seonjin Na
- · Korean Patent (With Samsung Electronics); Filling Date: 2021/07/23;

Efficient Encryption Method and Apparatus for Hardware-based Secure GPU Memory

- · Jaehyuk Huh, Seonjin Na, Sunho Lee, Yeonjae Kim, and Jongse Park
- · Korea Patent; Filling Date: 2020/11/23; Isseud Date: 2022/02/16

AWARDS AND HONORS

Best Paper Award

2022

· TNPU: Supporting Trusted Execution with Tree-less Integrity Protection for Neural Processing Unit, 3th place

National Scholarship

Mar. 2016 - 2023 Feb

· KAIST

Smumma CumLaude

Feb. 2016

· Sogang University

Gold Prize

Nov. 2015

· The 2015 ACM-ICPC Asia Daejeon Regional Contest 4th place

Honorable Mention

Nov. 2013

· The 2013 ACM-ICPC Asia Daejeon Regional Contest 13th place

Academic Scholarship, 8 semesters

Mar. 2012 - Sep. 2015

· Sogang University

ACADEMIC SERVICES

- · AE Program Committee: International Symposium on Computer Architecture (ISCA) 2024
- · **Discussion Modeartor**: GPGPU Workshop 2024
- · Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing 2023
- · Reviewer: IEEE Computer Architecture Letter 2023
- · WebChair: IEEE Computer Society TCuARCH

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

KAIST

- · CS510 Computer Architecture: Spring 2020
- · CS230 System Programming: Fall 2016, Spring 2017, Fall 2018, Fall 2020
- \cdot CS311 Computer Organization: Fall 2019

Sogang University

· Introduction to C Programming: Winter 2014

SKILLS

- \cdot Programming Languages : C/C++, Go, CUDA, Python, Java
- · Library/Frameworks : NVBit, Pytorch, Tensorflow
- · Simulators: SST-Sim, GPGPU-Sim, MGPU-Sim, Gem5, Gem5-gpu, Scale-Sim, ChampSim